Giovanni Pollo

Embedded System Engineering

+39 3407435788 giovannipollo98@gmail.com Via Meucci 7, Voghera (PV), 27058

INTRODUCTION

The interest and passion for scientific and technological subjects allowed me to obtain a grade of 101/110 in a three-year degree at the Politecnico di Torino.

The experiences abroad formed me both under the cultural and relational aspect and have increased my independence and problemsolving ability.

EDUCATION

Master's degree in Embedded Systems

Politecnico Di Torino | 2020 - 2022

Bachelor's degree in Electronic Engineering

Politecnico Di Torino | 2017 - 2020

SKILLS

- Embedded Systems
- Linux
- C, C++, Bash, LaTeX, VHDL, Verilog, CUDA
- Digital Design, Hardware Design
- Network basics
- Cybersecurity for Embedded Systems

CERTIFICATION

Cambridge C1 Advanced

Milan | 2016

Cambridge B2 First

Milan | 2015



EXPERIENCE

Children's Supervisor

Astro Park Tallaght, Dublin | July 2017 - September 2017

- · Improvements in the English language
- · First approach to a work environment
- Ability to manage a group of people
- Deadlines

Study abroad

Joseph Chamberlain Sixth Form College, Birmingham | August 2016 - December 2016

- Improvements in the English language
- · Get in touch with different cultures
- Deadlines
- Participation in many group project
- Ability to live abroad

PROJECTS

DLX Microprocessor Design

Politecnico Di Torino | March 2021 - July 2021

- VHDL structural design
- Windowed register file
- Five Stages Pipeline
- Enhanced Booth's Multiplier
- Hazard detection

CUDA Video Streaming

Politecnico Di Torino | September 2021 - February 2022

- Fully functional on NVIDIA Jetson Nano board
- Maximum parallellism with threads and kernels
- Comparison between CPU and GPU performance
- Independent module for higher scalability